This was just my political
economies class finals. Um like
what I wrote for the final but
it sounded good so I have to
share. Sorry. Um I was just
talking about austerity and
examples of successful
implementations of of austerity
in the western kind of economic
sphere. Let's go. Um austerity
was initially a project coined
by the capitalist state and
economist to foreclose all
demands for an alternative
society after World War one.
However, it's everlasting
ability to restabolize capital
accumulation inspired many
countries down the passing of
time to follow in the footsteps
of their European predecessors.
Two examples of successful
austerity implementations are
Italy under Bonito Mussolini's
fascist regime and Chile under
Augusto Pinosha's military
dictatorship. Though these two
cases were from unrelated parts
of the world.